Finding Aid for the Dee Caruso papers LSC.2174
UCLA Library Special Collections
Dee Caruso papers
1965-1979
UCLA Library Special Collections
Caruso, Dee
Caruso, Sandra
LSC.2174
2.6 linear feet (4 boxes and 1 flat box)
2 linear feet (2 unprocessed doc boxes, 1 unprocessed flat box)
Dee Caruso has written for film and television. The collection consists of files related to Caruso career representing projects such as Get Smart, and The World's Greatest Athlete, among others.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Sandra Caruso, 2013.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9973817803606533
Biography
Dee Caruso got his start in comedy as a writer for nightclub comedians such as Don Adams and Martin and Rossi. He and his writing partner Gerald Gardner went on to write shows for comedians likes of Jack Benny, Jerry Lewis, Don Rickles and other popular entertainers of the time. Caruso and Gardner were the head writers for the original TV series Get Smart. They also penned an unusual game show, Screen Test, which featured, Don Adams. The team created and served as head writers and producers of the television series, The Monkees. Additionally, Caruso co-produced and co-wrote a situation comedy pilot called the Pickle Brothers, starring the comedy team The Uncalled For Three. They also worked together on television movies including, How to Break Up a Happy Divorce and Break Up. His feature film credits include The World's Greatest Athlete, Which Way to the Front, and Doin' Time. Caruso received an Emmy nomination for his work on That Was the Week That Was with David Frost.
Caruso co-taught a class with his wife, Sandra Caruso, What's Funny, What's Not at UCLA Extension for 10 years and after that became a professor of screenwriting at UCLA School of Theater, Film and Television for more than 20 years. Dee Caruso died May 27, 2012, in Brentwood, CA.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of script material and small amount of clippings, and publicity documenting the career of comedy writer Dee Caruso. The television writings represent produced and unproduced projects including Get Smart!, Gilligan's Island, The Monkees, and The Smothers Brothers, among others. Motion picture projects include Which Way to the Front and The World's Greatest Athelete.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Motion Picture Projects
Television Projects
Unidentified Projects
Television comedy writers -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- Archives.; Caruso, Dee; Caruso, Sandra
- Motion Picture Projects
  - Canary Sings at Midnight (The) - script, no date (Box 3)
  - Closet Skeleton (The) - script, no date (Box 3)
  - Drag: The Story of Two Straight Guys Who are Female Impersonators - script, no date (Box 3)
  - Fair Catch - script (duplicate copy) (unproduced), no date (Box 3)
  - Hardluck Kid (The) - script, no date (Box 1)
  - I Love Rosa -script, no date (Box 4)
  - I'd Bet my Wife - outline, no date (Box 4)
  - Marry me, Marry me - script and synopsis, 1978 Jan 24 (Box 2)
  - Which Way to the Front - final white script, no date (Box 2)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - annotated first draft screenplay, 1971 Oct 18 (Box 2)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - cartoon strips (8 items), no date (Box 5)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - ephemera and clippings, c. 1973 (Box 3)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - Paperback book, 1973 (Box 3)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - press book, c. 1973 (Box 3)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - reviews in Time, Parents and Better Family Living, New York, and Seventeen magazines, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The) - Variety ads, 1972 Feb and Oct (Box 4)
  - World's Greatest Athlete (The)- shooting script, 1972 Feb 21 (Box 3)
- Television Projects
  - Adventures of Freddie - pilot script, 1977 Jan 7 (Box 1)
  - Arte Johnson Show (The): Call Holme - shooting script, 1971 Nov 10 (Box 1)
  - Attorneys at Law - presentation, no date (Box 3)
  - Aviators (The) - pilot script, 1967 June 13 (Box 3)
  - Boss's Son (The) - script, no date (Box 3)
  - Breakup: or is Spiro Agnew Eligible for Unemployment? - poster, no date (Box 5)
  - Call me a Cop - concept and characters, 1974 Aug (Box 3)
  - Chip Off the Old Block -concept, no date (Box 3)
  - David Steinberg Show (The) - rough draft script, 1972 June (Box 1)
  - David Steinberg Show (The) - script, 1972 July 7 (Box 1)
  - Fireman's Ball - pilot script, 1974 Feb 20 (Box 1)
  - Freebish of Scotland Yard - presentation, no date (Box 4)
  - Get Smart!: original show (#1) - script, 1965 April 29 (Box 1)
  - Get Smart!: Diplomat's Daughter (The) - script, 1965 July 8 (Box 1)
  - Get Smart!: Greatest Spy on Earth (The) - script, 1966 Aug 23 (Box 1)
  - Get Smart!: The Expendable Agent - script, 1967 Jan 7 (Box 1)
  - Get Smart!: Too Many Chiefs - script, 1965 Aug 23 (Box 1)
  - Get Smart!: Washington 4 - Indians 3 - script, 1965 July 15 (Box 1)
  - Get Smart!: Weekend Vampire - script, 1965 Sept 22 (Box 1)
  - Ghost and Mrs. Muir (The): Medium Well Done - script, 1969 June 10 (Box 4)
  - Gilligan's Island: Producer (The) - script, 1966 May 26 (Box 1)
  - Help Inc. - final shooting script, 1971 Nov 30 (Box 1)
  - Hocus Pocus Gang (The) - treatment, 1966 Jan 13 (Box 1)
  - How to Break up a Happy Divorce - script, 1976 Mar 18 (Box 2)
  - Love American Style: Love and the Waitress - script, no date (Box 2)
  - Manley and the Mob - presentation, no date (Box 4)
  - Marriage Counselors (The)- premise and pilot story, no date (Box 4)
  - Monkees (The): Spy Who Came in from the Cool (The) - script, 1966 May 16 (Box 2)
  - Pickle Brothers - pilot script and advance program information promotional item, 1967 Jan 6 (Box 2)
  - Pickle Brothers - production information, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Pickle Brothers - script pages, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Sedgewick Hawk-Styles Prince of Danger: Upside Down Murder (The) - script, 1967 Mar 1 (Box 4)
  - Sheik (The) - presentation, no date (Box 4)
  - Sledge Hammer: 28 Hours - script, no date (Box 4)
  - Smothers Brothers (The): Halo In the Ring - script, 1965 Sept 10 (Box 2)
  - Stay in the Car and Keep the Motor Running - presentation, no date (Box 4)
  - Tay-Gar King of the Jungle - script and advance program information promotional item, 1966 Nov-Dec (Box 2)
  - This is Barney Starker - script, no date (Box 4)
  - Underwood Luger - script, no date (Box 4)
  - Where's the Fire: New Candidate (The) - script, 1974 July 19 (Box 2)
  - Where's the Fire?!: Beauty Contest (The) - script, 1974 Sept 25 (Box 2)
  - Where's the Fire?!: Inspection (The) - script, 1974 Oct 24 (Box 2)
  - Without Reservations - script and press information, 1975 Jan 27 (Box 2)
  - You Call This Living? - presentation, no date (Box 4)
  - Your Place or Mine? - pilot script, 1979 Sept 7 (Box 4)
- Unidentified Projects
  - Great Dinosaur Robbery (The) - script, 1972 Dec 15 (Box 4)
  - Have I got a Girl for you - annotated script, no date (Box 4)
  - Spittin' Image - script, no date (Box 4)
  - There Goes the Neighborhood! - script, no date (Box 4)
  - This May Hurt a Little - treatment, 1968 Jan 22 (Box 4)